FELESHIA WEST

Kyle, Texas 78640 Cell: 512-938-9435 feleshiawest@gmail.com

Summary

As a tech savvy accountant with a career change in IT, I bring a unique combination of skills in critical thinking, data-driven decisions, and problem solving. My previous experience in Finance/Accounting has equipped me with a solid foundation in attention to detail, interpreting complex data sets, strong communication, and passion for technology.

Education

- **Bachelor of Science, Information Technology** Dec/2023 Western Governors University Salt Lake City, Utah
- Master in Business Administration 2017 Western Governors University – Salt Lake City, Utah
- Bachelor of Business Administration in Accounting 2013 Texas State University – San Marcos, Texas

Skills

• Excel, SQL, Tableau, Python, GitHub/Git, Power BI, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, MicroStrategy, SharePoint, Business Objects, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Portfolio

- https://feleshia33.github.io/MartiTheAnalyst.github.io/
 - o This portfolio showcases my experience using different skills within provided projects.

Experience

Aerospace Medical Technician Supervisor, MSgt United States Air Force Reserves, San Antonio, Texas

03/2004 - Present

Accountant II (remote)

01/2022- 3/2023

Truckstop.com, Boise, Idaho

- Recorded bi-weekly payroll and payroll funding journal entries.
- Reconciled bi-weekly payroll including research and resolution of variances identified by comparing payroll data to tax remittance and other supporting documentation.
- Tracked and reconciliation of employee and employer benefit deductions.
- Served as the primary accounting contact for P&C to resolve benefit issues and questions.
- Served as the primary accounting contact for the payroll department including responding to queries on how to handle specific payroll issues and general ledger mapping.
- Performed accounting and reconciliation for partner paid time off (PTO) entries.
- Participated in the preparation of monthly account variance analysis for assigned accounts.

FELESHIA WEST

Kyle, Texas 78640 Cell: 512-938-9435 feleshiawest@gmail.com

• Participated in period-end close activities including the preparation and review of journal entries and review and analysis of financial data and reports.

Corporate Accountant (hybrid)

06/2021-1/2022

J&J Worldwide Services, Austin, Texas

- Prepares and analyze job cost reports, to include posting of expense and revenue accruals.
- Reviews fixed assets, reconcile the fixed asset ledger, and prepare reports.
- Communicates and collect payment from customers and record it into the system.
- Creates and record financial transactions with journal entries or system imports.
- Reviews Accounts Payable transactions for coding accuracy.
- Prepares monthly Revenue Tax reports, Sales Tax reports and Financial Statement.

Accountant 10/2020- 05/2021

Austin Cancer Centers, Austin, Texas

- Processed accounts payable and ensure invoices are coded with correct GL codes.
- Prepared and book journal entries for fixed assets and monthly depreciation.
- Preparation and reconciliation of month-end journal entries, accruals and reports.
- Bank and credit card, month-end account reconciliations & month end financial package.
- Follow up with vendor issues and inquires for payment and sales tax.
- Reviewed employee expense reports for proper classification and payment.
- Reconciled vendor statements and respond to vendor inquiries on a timely basis.

Accountant 04/2018 – 8/2019

City of Austin, Austin, Texas

- Prepared daily cash receipts (CR) and online payments.
- Processed travel advances and claims and issue travel reimbursement.
- Maintained vendor refund log and resolve discrepancies and process refunds/chargebacks.
- Internal and external problem solving, resolving billing, invoicing, and financial inquiries.
- Revamped the CR process of recording revenue and reduced month-end close by 30%.

Staff Accountant 04/2015 – 5/2017

HCA - St. David's Healthcare, Austin, Texas

- Performed monthly vendor invoicing of sales/purchases and calculated sales tax due.
- Prepared daily operating reports and supporting schedules sent to the Controller.
- Analyzed budget variances monthly and prepared analysis summarizing explanations.
- Maintained detailed general ledger reconciliations and processed adjustments.
- Maintained assigned subsidiary records to support general ledger control account balances.
- Prepared reconciliations for all balance sheet accounts assigned on a monthly basis.